{
    "time": 30,
    "maxQuestions": 50,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Who invented Python?",
            "options": [
                "Sir Alex Ferguson",
                "Haskell",
                "Lionel and Ritchie",
                "Von Rossum",
                "Alan Turing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Von Rossum"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first name of Python's inventor is ______________",
            "options": [
                "Ferguson",
                "Nghutor",
                "Guido",
                "Guiseppe",
                "Galdo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Guido"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of following python code?\nprint(5 % 3)",
            "options": [
                "15",
                "125",
                "5",
                "3",
                "53",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "The elementary data types in python are __________",
            "options": [
                "int, string and float",
                "long, string and double",
                "binary, ternary and hexadecimal",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int, string and float"
        },
        {
            "question": "The earliest computing device is the __________",
            "options": [
                "Analytical Engine",
                "Difference Engine",
                "Abacus",
                "First Generation Computer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Abacus"
        },
        {
            "question": "A physical computer system is made up of _________ main parts.",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "3",
                "4",
                "5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The parts that make up a computer system are __________",
            "options": [
                "Input, Processing and Output",
                "Software, Hardware and Others",
                "Software, Hardware and Peopleware",
                "Bits, Nibbles and Bytes"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Input, Processing and Output"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1614, __________ invented the logarithm and decimals notation",
            "options": [
                "Luke Cage",
                "Alan Turing",
                "John Napier",
                "Lady Ada Lovelace",
                "Von Neumann"
            ],
            "correctOption": "John Napier"
        },
        {
            "question": "John Napier created the Napier's Bones to aid in __________",
            "options": [
                "Addition and Subtraction",
                "Multiplication and Division",
                "Exponentiation",
                "Calculating square roots"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Multiplication and Division"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Slide Rule was invented in _________",
            "options": [
                "1619",
                "1620",
                "1621",
                "1622"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1620"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who Invented the Napier's Bones?",
            "options": [
                "Daniel Bones",
                "William Bones",
                "William Oughted",
                "John Napier",
                "James Napier",
                "Jacob Napier"
            ],
            "correctOption": "John Napier"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who Invented the Slide Rule?",
            "options": [
                "Jacob Slide",
                "Willian",
                "Sylvester Rule",
                "William Oughted",
                "William Shakespeare",
                "Charles Babbage"
            ],
            "correctOption": "William Oughted"
        },
        {
            "question": "The symbol 'X' for multiplication was introduced by who?",
            "options": [
                "John Napier",
                "Euler",
                "William Oughted",
                "Isaac Newton",
                "Francis Bacon"
            ],
            "correctOption": "William Oughted"
        },
        {
            "question": "In mathematics, binary numbers are represented using two different symbols namely; _______________",
            "options": [
                "0s and 1s",
                "True and False",
                "Alpha and Omega"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0s and 1s"
        },
        {
            "question": "_____________ created the cipher system",
            "options": [
                "Francis Bacon",
                "Hacker James",
                "Emperor Nero",
                "Cassius",
                "Lady Ada Lovelace",
                "Philip Emeagwali"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Francis Bacon"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ciper system was created in __________",
            "options": [
                "1625",
                "1624",
                "1623",
                "1622"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1623"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Pascal programming language was created by __________",
            "options": [
                "Blaise Pascal",
                "William Shockley",
                "Nicklaus Wirth",
                "G. Van Rossum"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nicklaus Wirth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why did Blaise Pascal start working on the Pascaline?",
            "options": [
                "To help galvanise the French Revolution",
                "To ease his father's tax collection job",
                "To help him in his mathematics assignment",
                "To start a business"
            ],
            "correctOption": "To ease his father's tax collection job"
        },
        {
            "question": "___________ invented differential and integral calculus",
            "options": [
                "Euler",
                "Hiro",
                "The Greek",
                "Leibniz",
                "The Romans"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Leibniz"
        },
        {
            "question": "Joseph Marie Jacquard was a french ____________",
            "options": [
                "beggar",
                "weaver and merchant",
                "royal",
                "politician",
                "software engineer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "weaver and merchant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who invented the Jacquard Loom?",
            "options": [
                "Joseph Marie Jacquard",
                "Japheth Marie Jacquard",
                "John Marie Jacquard",
                "Jacob Marie Jacquard"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Joseph Marie Jacquard"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is referred to as the father of computing?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Isaac Newton",
                "Joseph Jaquard",
                "Blaise Pascal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Difference Engine invented?",
            "options": [
                "1819",
                "1820",
                "1821",
                "1822"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1821"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first programmable computer was the __________",
            "options": [
                "Difference Engine",
                "Analytical Engine",
                "ENIAC",
                "EDVAC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Analytical Engine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lady Ada Lovelace was a _______________",
            "options": [
                "Mathematician and Scientist",
                "Poet",
                "Housewife",
                "Carpenter"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mathematician and Scientist"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 'Ada' programming language was named after __________",
            "options": [
                "Ada Okafor",
                "Adama David",
                "Adah Ameh",
                "Ada Love",
                "Ada Lovelace",
                "Ada Babbage"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ada Lovelace"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ invented Boolean Algebra",
            "options": [
                "John Bull",
                "John Boole",
                "George Boole",
                "George Bull"
            ],
            "correctOption": "George Boole"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ founded the company that later became IBM",
            "options": [
                "Herman Hollerith",
                "Mark Zuckerberg",
                "Ibrahim Mensah",
                "Bill Gates",
                "Larry Ellison"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Herman Hollerith"
        },
        {
            "question": "Herman Hollerith's tabulating machine was based on the use of ___________",
            "options": [
                "Microprocessors",
                "Punched Cards",
                "Integrated Circuits",
                "Vacuum Tubes"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Punched Cards"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tabulating Machine Company later became ____________",
            "options": [
                "International Business Machines",
                "International Booking Machines",
                "International Tabulation Corporation",
                "International Binary Machines",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "International Business Machines"
        },
        {
            "question": "Python is a _________ language",
            "options": [
                "Bulky",
                "High level",
                "Static",
                "Low level",
                "1st generation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "High level"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert A336A₁₆ to base 10?",
            "options": [
                "10100011001101101010",
                "668523",
                "668522",
                "2431552",
                "42"
            ],
            "correctOption": "668522"
        },
        {
            "question": "Computer systems are usually and integration of two entities; namely ______________",
            "options": [
                "0s and 1s",
                "Hardware and Software",
                "Desktop and Keyboard"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Hardware and Software"
        },
        {
            "question": "A computer's hardware components can be classified into all these except?",
            "options": [
                "Input devices",
                "Output devices",
                "Processing devices",
                "Storage devices",
                "Memory",
                "Software applications"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Software applications"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a hardware component?",
            "options": [
                "Monitor",
                "Keyboard",
                "Printer",
                "Microsoft Word"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Microsoft Word"
        },
        {
            "question": "The most common keyboard layout is __________",
            "options": [
                "QWERTY",
                "DVORAK",
                "QWERTZ",
                "ABCDEF"
            ],
            "correctOption": "QWERTY"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ___________ is referred to as the brains of the computer",
            "options": [
                "CPU",
                "Monitor",
                "User",
                "Operating System",
                "Windows 10"
            ],
            "correctOption": "CPU"
        },
        {
            "question": "CPU is short for ____________",
            "options": [
                "Central Processor Unit",
                "Central Intelligence Unit",
                "Central Processing Unit",
                "Control Processing Unit"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Central Processing Unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "The speed of a CPU can be determined by clock rate",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lady Ada Lovelace is considered by many to be the first programmer",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "The functions of the CPU include all the below except",
            "options": [
                "To control the sequence of operations",
                "To control the usage of main memory",
                "To carry out processing",
                "To print out documents"
            ],
            "correctOption": "To print out documents"
        },
        {
            "question": "The two types of memory are RAM and ROM",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Control Unit and Arithmetic and Logic unit are not located in the CPU",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a processor manufacturer?",
            "options": [
                "Intel",
                "Nvidia",
                "AMD",
                "Zinox"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Zinox"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 2MB to KB",
            "options": [
                "1042",
                "1000",
                "2048",
                "1012",
                "2084"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2048"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 0.5GB to Bytes",
            "options": [
                "536870912",
                "524288",
                "512",
                "0.00048828125"
            ],
            "correctOption": "536870912"
        },
        {
            "question": "1 Terabyte is 1 billion bytes",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "1 Bytes is _______ bits",
            "options": [
                "18",
                "8",
                "16",
                "32",
                "64"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "1 Gigabyte is ________ bits",
            "options": [
                "1073741824",
                "8388608",
                "8589934592",
                "Infinity"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8589934592"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an output device?",
            "options": [
                "Monitor",
                "Speaker",
                "Scanner",
                "Printer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Scanner"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not and input device?",
            "options": [
                "CPU",
                "Keyboard",
                "Mouse",
                "Touchpad"
            ],
            "correctOption": "CPU"
        },
        {
            "question": "The computer monitor is usually called ___________",
            "options": [
                "Virtual Display Unit",
                "Visual Disk Unit",
                "Visual Display Unit",
                "Visual Display User"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Visual Display Unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "111111111₂ is equivalent to __________",
            "options": [
                "778₈",
                "512₁₀",
                "1FF₁₆",
                "111111111₁₀"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1FF₁₆"
        },
        {
            "question": "The only number system that the CPU understand is ________",
            "options": [
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal",
                "Octal",
                "Base 2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Base 2"
        },
        {
            "question": "The only number system that the CPU understand is ________",
            "options": [
                "Base 10",
                "Base 16",
                "Binary",
                "Ternary",
                "Tertiary",
                "Heptadecimal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Binary"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python, prefixing a number with '0b' indicates that the number is _________",
            "options": [
                "Binary",
                "Ternary",
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal",
                "Octal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Binary"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python, prefixing a number with '0o' indicates that the number is _________",
            "options": [
                "Binary",
                "Ternary",
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal",
                "Octal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Octal"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python, prefixing a number with '0x' indicates that the number is _________",
            "options": [
                "Binary",
                "Ternary",
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal",
                "Octal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Hexadecimal"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the following Python program?\n\ns = 1e5\nprint(s)",
            "options": [
                "1e5",
                "100000.0",
                "100000",
                "10000.0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "100000.0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The python interpreter will evaluate '1e23' as ___________",
            "options": [
                "1 x 23",
                "1 x 10²³",
                "1²³"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1 x 10²³"
        },
        {
            "question": "The two major versions of python currently being supported are _________ and ________",
            "options": [
                "2, 3",
                "3, 4",
                "4, 5",
                "1, 2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2, 3"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nprint(2**2)",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "2",
                "4",
                "8",
                "16"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nprint(2^2)",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "2",
                "4",
                "8",
                "16"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sum of 234₈ and 345₈ is _________ ₁₀",
            "options": [
                "88",
                "579",
                "385",
                "358"
            ],
            "correctOption": "385"
        },
        {
            "question": "100011110₂ - 1111111₂ equals _________ ₂",
            "options": [
                "10011111",
                "100111111",
                "100011111",
                "10011011"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10011111"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert ABC₁₆ to Base 10",
            "options": [
                "2748",
                "7482",
                "2478",
                "4872"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2748"
        },
        {
            "question": "ABC₁₆ + DEF₁₆ = _________ ₁₆",
            "options": [
                "ABCDEF",
                "18AB",
                "ACDF",
                "FFF",
                "FEDCBA"
            ],
            "correctOption": "18AB"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 777₈ to Hexadecimal",
            "options": [
                "1FF₁₆",
                "1F₁₆",
                "FF₁₆",
                "777₁₆"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1FF₁₆"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 10000000111₂ to Decimal",
            "options": [
                "1030",
                "1031",
                "1032",
                "1033"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1031"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 765 to Binary",
            "options": [
                "1011111101₂",
                "1001111101₂",
                "1111111101₂",
                "1001111101₂"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1011111101₂"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sum of 11011111₁₀ and 100000₁₀ is __________ ₁₀",
            "options": [
                "11111111",
                "255",
                "254",
                "256"
            ],
            "correctOption": "11111111"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate the following python code\n\nname = 'Dr. Dave'\nprint(name[3:])",
            "options": [
                "Dr.",
                "Dr. Dave",
                "Dave",
                "Dr. Dave 3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Dave"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\na = 2\nb = 3\nprint(a**b)",
            "options": [
                "6",
                "23",
                "8",
                "9"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "ENIAC means _____________",
            "options": [
                "Electronic Numerical Integrator and Computer",
                "Electronic Numerical Integrator and Calculator",
                "Electric Numerical Integrator and Computer",
                "Electric Numerical Integrator and Calculator",
                "Electronic Napier Integrator and Computer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Electronic Numerical Integrator and Computer"
        },
        {
            "question": "RAM means ____________",
            "options": [
                "Daft Punk",
                "Random Access Memory",
                "Real-Time Access Memory",
                "Read Access Memory"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Random Access Memory"
        },
        {
            "question": "ROM means ____________",
            "options": [
                "Read Only Memory",
                "Random Only Memory",
                "Real-Time Only Memory",
                "Read Access Machine"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Read Only Memory"
        },
        {
            "question": "EDVAC means _____________",
            "options": [
                "Electronic Discreet Variable Automatic Computer",
                "Electric Discrete Variable Automatic Computer",
                "Electronic Discrete Variable Automatic Computer",
                "Electronic Discrete Variable Automatic Calculator",
                "Electric Discrete Variable Automatic Calculator"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Electronic Discrete Variable Automatic Computer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which came first, ENIAC or EDVAC?",
            "options": [
                "ENIAC",
                "EDVAC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ENIAC"
        },
        {
            "question": "1 Byte is equivalent to 8 bits",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "32 bits is equivalent to 8 Bytes",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the smallest unit of memory on the computer?",
            "options": [
                "Word",
                "Byte",
                "Bit",
                "Double"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bit"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nlst = [0,1,2,3]\nprint(lst[0])",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "2",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nlst = [0,1,2,3]\nprint(len(lst))",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nans = 'No'\nprint(ans * 3)",
            "options": [
                "No3",
                "3No",
                "NNNooo",
                "NoNoNo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NoNoNo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python code?\n\nlst = [0,1,2,3]\nprint(lst[-1])",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "2",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of 2 % 3",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "3",
                "6",
                "8"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nnum = 0x535\nprint(num)",
            "options": [
                "0x535",
                "535",
                "1333",
                "x535"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1333"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nfoo = 3\nprint(foo)",
            "options": [
                "foo3",
                "3foo",
                "3",
                "foo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nmessage = 'Correct'\nprint(num)",
            "options": [
                "It will result in an error",
                "Correct",
                "Error",
                "num"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It will result in an error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Comments in python start with ________",
            "options": [
                "#",
                "@",
                "//",
                "/*",
                "-",
                "$"
            ],
            "correctOption": "#"
        },
        {
            "question": "Comments in python start with a/an _________",
            "options": [
                "Square Bracket",
                "Hash Sign",
                "Dollar Sign",
                "Asterisk",
                "Hyphen"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Hash Sign"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the types of computer software?",
            "options": [
                "System and Application software",
                "Vertical and Horizontal software",
                "Hardware and Software",
                "Microsoft Word and Corel Draw"
            ],
            "correctOption": "System and Application software"
        },
        {
            "question": "Something that holds a value that may change is called a/an __________",
            "options": [
                "constant",
                "variable",
                "holder",
                "memory",
                "storage space"
            ],
            "correctOption": "variable"
        },
        {
            "question": "Something that holds a value that cannot be changed is called a _________",
            "options": [
                "constant",
                "variable",
                "holder",
                "memory",
                "storage space"
            ],
            "correctOption": "constant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who invented the first true calculating (adding) machine?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Con Leibniz",
                "Joseph Marie Jacquard",
                "Blaise Pascal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Blaise Pascal"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the meaning of IBM?",
            "options": [
                "International Business Machines",
                "Internal Business Machines",
                "Internet Business Machines",
                "Internet Binary Machines",
                "International Binary Machines"
            ],
            "correctOption": "International Business Machines"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nx = 5\ny = x + 3\nx = x - 1\nz = 10\nx = x + z\nprint(x, y, z)",
            "options": [
                "14 8 10",
                "8 10 14",
                "10 14 8",
                "x y z"
            ],
            "correctOption": "14 8 10"
        },
        {
            "question": "The \\n literal means __________",
            "options": [
                "newline",
                "carriage return",
                "backspace",
                "tab",
                "vertical tab"
            ],
            "correctOption": "newline"
        },
        {
            "question": "The \\t literal means __________",
            "options": [
                "newline",
                "carriage return",
                "backspace",
                "tab",
                "vertical tab"
            ],
            "correctOption": "tab"
        },
        {
            "question": "The \\b literal means __________",
            "options": [
                "newline",
                "carriage return",
                "backspace",
                "tab",
                "vertical tab"
            ],
            "correctOption": "backspace"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nl = [1, 2, 3]\nprint(l[:])",
            "options": [
                "[1, 2, 3]",
                "1",
                "2",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "[1, 2, 3]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nl = [1, 2, 3]\nprint(l[1:])",
            "options": [
                "[2, 3]",
                "[1, 2]",
                "[1, 2, 3]",
                "1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "[2, 3]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nl = [1, 2, 3]\nprint(l[:1])",
            "options": [
                "[1]",
                "1",
                "[2]",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "[1]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of the following expression in python?\n4**0.5",
            "options": [
                "2.0",
                "2.5",
                "4.0",
                "0.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2.0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What best describes the output of the following python expression?\nfor i in range(10):\n\tprint('Hello, Lohysey!!!')",
            "options": [
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 9 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 10 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 11 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 1 time",
                "It will throw an exception"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 10 times"
        },
        {
            "question": "What best describes the output of the following python expression?\nfor i in range(1, 10):\n\tprint('Hello, Lohysey!!!')",
            "options": [
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 9 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 10 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 11 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 1 time",
                "It will throw an exception"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 9 times"
        },
        {
            "question": "What best describes the output of the following python expression?\nfor i in range(10, 10):\n\tprint('Hello, Lohysey!!!')",
            "options": [
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 9 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 10 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 11 times",
                "It will print 'Hello, Lohysey!!!' 1 time",
                "It will throw an exception",
                "It will not print anything"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It will not print anything"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of combining multiple strings is called ________",
            "options": [
                "concatenation",
                "splitting",
                "indenting",
                "addition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "concatenation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nf = 'Nathaniel'\nl = 'Danaan'\nprint(f + l)",
            "options": [
                "Nathaniel Danaan",
                "Danaan",
                "NathanielDanaan",
                "Nathaniel",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NathanielDanaan"
        },
        {
            "question": "The input function in python allows us to take input from the keyboard",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nt = 'Introduction to Computer Science'\nprint(t.capitalize())",
            "options": [
                "Introduction to computer science",
                "Introduction To Computer Science",
                "introduction to computer science",
                "INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Introduction to computer science"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nt = 'Introduction to Computer Science'\nprint(t.upper())",
            "options": [
                "Introduction to computer science",
                "Introduction To Computer Science",
                "introduction to computer science",
                "INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nt = 'Introduction to Computer Science'\nprint(t.lower())",
            "options": [
                "Introduction to computer science",
                "Introduction To Computer Science",
                "introduction to computer science",
                "INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "introduction to computer science"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following python program?\n\nt = 'Introduction to Computer Science'\nprint(t.title())",
            "options": [
                "Introduction to computer science",
                "Introduction To Computer Science",
                "introduction to computer science",
                "INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Introduction To Computer Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "What category of programming language is python",
            "options": [
                "Machine language",
                "Low level language",
                "mid level language",
                "high level language"
            ],
            "correctOption": "high level language"
        },
        {
            "question": "print len(\"this is\")\r\nThe output of the code block above is?",
            "options": [
                "7",
                "6",
                "5",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "7"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is not a primitive data type in python",
            "options": [
                "bool",
                "int",
                "count",
                "float"
            ],
            "correctOption": "count"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following program will evaluate to?\r\n2<<2",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "8",
                "6",
                "12"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following program will evaluate to?\r\n13/6**3-4/2",
            "options": [
                "-4",
                "-2",
                "2",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-2"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is not an input device",
            "options": [
                "Joy-stick",
                "Light-pen",
                "iPad",
                "mouse"
            ],
            "correctOption": "iPad"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate the following program block?\n\n1<3&3==7/2",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "9=3",
                "9"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a field in computer science",
            "options": [
                "Data mining",
                "Artificial Intelligence",
                "Chemo-synthesis",
                "Robotics"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Chemo-synthesis"
        },
        {
            "question": "The father of the computer is",
            "options": [
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Blaise Pascal",
                "Pythagoras",
                "Bill Gate"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following features is not desirable in computers",
            "options": [
                "Accuracy",
                "Integrity",
                "volatility",
                "versatility "
            ],
            "correctOption": "volatility"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the binary equivalence of the decimal number 567?",
            "options": [
                "1000110110",
                "1000110111",
                "1100110111",
                "1000110100"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1000110111"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 10101000101₂ to decimal",
            "options": [
                "1244",
                "1344",
                "1348",
                "1349"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1349"
        },
        {
            "question": "Compute the following leaving your answer in hexadecimal\r\n140-108",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "20",
                "30",
                "40"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the meaning of the Acronym BCD",
            "options": [
                "Big Code Debugger",
                "Binary Coded Decimal",
                "Binary Computer Data",
                "Base coding Digits"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Binary Coded Decimal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert F1FA from hexadecimal to binary",
            "options": [
                "1111000011111010",
                "1111000100111010",
                "1111000111111010",
                "1111000111111000"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1111000111111010"
        },
        {
            "question": "The output to the following program is?\r\n\"5\"+\"5\"",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "5",
                "50",
                "55"
            ],
            "correctOption": "55"
        },
        {
            "question": "print (int(\"5\"+\"0\") + len(\"university of Jos\"))\r\nwhats is the output?",
            "options": [
                "17",
                "37",
                "67",
                "87"
            ],
            "correctOption": "67"
        },
        {
            "question": "print not (30<30)\r\nwhat will be the output",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "Error",
                "False",
                "30"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 313 to base 8",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "201",
                "202",
                "203"
            ],
            "correctOption": "203"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 430 from octal to base hexadecimal",
            "options": [
                "118",
                "117",
                "116",
                "115"
            ],
            "correctOption": "118"
        },
        {
            "question": "a = [2,3,5,6,7]\nprint(a[3])\n\nWhat is the output of the above program?",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "5",
                "6",
                "7"
            ],
            "correctOption": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate in python\n\n2**3*4**5-192",
            "options": [
                "4000",
                "6000",
                "7000",
                "8000"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8000"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the data type of the following line of code?\n\nx<y",
            "options": [
                "int",
                "bool",
                "float",
                "str"
            ],
            "correctOption": "bool"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the data type of the following line of code?\n\nlen(x)",
            "options": [
                "int",
                "bool",
                "float",
                "str"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the data type of the following line of code?\n\n\"5\"*2",
            "options": [
                "int",
                "bool",
                "float",
                "str"
            ],
            "correctOption": "str"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following line of code?\n\nprint(\"4\"*4)",
            "options": [
                "16",
                "44",
                "4444",
                "20"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4444"
        },
        {
            "question": "the native computer only understands _____________",
            "options": [
                "Hexadecimal",
                "Binary",
                "decimal",
                "0s"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Binary"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following number bases is least relevant to computers?",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "2",
                "8",
                "16"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "Operator precedence is applicable in ____________",
            "options": [
                "Arithmetic",
                "Binary system",
                "data types",
                "printing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Arithmetic"
        },
        {
            "question": "The most relevant number base in computer science is?",
            "options": [
                "16",
                "10",
                "8",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements are true?\n int f(float);",
            "options": [
                "f is a function taking an argument of type int and returning a floating point number",
                "f is a function taking an argument of type float and returning a integer. ",
                "f is a function of type float ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "f is a function taking an argument of type float and returning a integer. "
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is not a component of the computer system",
            "options": [
                "Input",
                "ALU",
                "Control",
                "Device"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Device"
        },
        {
            "question": "VLSI in evolution of computer memory means?",
            "options": [
                "Very Low Storage Interface",
                "Very Large Storage Interface",
                "Very Large Scale Integration",
                "Very Low Scale Integration"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Very Large Scale Integration"
        },
        {
            "question": "The generation of computer that is concerned with computers making decisions like humans is?",
            "options": [
                "5th generation",
                "4th generation",
                "3rd generation",
                "2nd generation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "5th generation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Boolean algebra is used to simplify?",
            "options": [
                "Number Systems",
                "Logical Equations",
                "Arithmetic",
                "Logical symbols"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Logical Equations"
        },
        {
            "question": "Determine the output of the following line of code\n\nprint int(float(1/2))",
            "options": [
                "0.5",
                "0.0",
                "0",
                "1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does ASCII mean",
            "options": [
                "American System for Code Information Interchange",
                "American Standard Code for Information Internet",
                "American Standard Code for Information Interchange",
                "Arithmetic Standard Code for Information Interchange"
            ],
            "correctOption": "American Standard Code for Information Interchange"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following is not used when writing a python program",
            "options": [
                "Computer System",
                "Operating System",
                "Automated Teller",
                "Debugger"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Automated Teller"
        },
        {
            "question": "Convert 677 to base 8",
            "options": [
                "1244",
                "1542",
                "1425",
                "1245"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1245"
        },
        {
            "question": "convert 101010111010₂ from binary to base 16",
            "options": [
                "ABA",
                "A00",
                "A770",
                "BAA"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ABA"
        },
        {
            "question": "convert 1010101010101₂ to octal and hexadecimal respectively",
            "options": [
                "12225, 1555",
                "12225, AAA1",
                "12525, 1555",
                "12525, AAA1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "12525, 1555"
        },
        {
            "question": "Artificial Intelligence is also known as _____________",
            "options": [
                "Fast Systems",
                "Machine Learning",
                "Static Data",
                "Networking"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Machine Learning"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the singular of Data?",
            "options": [
                "Database",
                "Character",
                "Datum",
                "Num",
                "Dati",
                "Dato"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Datum"
        },
        {
            "question": "The field of Computer Science that specializes in interconnections between devices is know as?",
            "options": [
                "Internet Studies",
                "Wiring",
                "Programming",
                "Networking"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Networking"
        },
        {
            "question": "A data structure that allows repetition of a program code segment is called?",
            "options": [
                "Loop",
                "Bug",
                "Real",
                "Return"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Loop"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python, values are gotten from functions using the keyword _____________",
            "options": [
                "unite",
                "return",
                "get",
                "program",
                "hide"
            ],
            "correctOption": "return"
        },
        {
            "question": "An organized pool of data is also called?",
            "options": [
                "Sector",
                "Segment",
                "Database",
                "Information center"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Database"
        },
        {
            "question": "A program is a sequence of",
            "options": [
                "data",
                "instructions",
                "data types",
                "database"
            ],
            "correctOption": "instructions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Programming error due to wrong spelling is known as?",
            "options": [
                "Semantic error",
                "Logical error",
                "Syntax error",
                "computational error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Syntax error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Programming error due to wrong logic is known as?",
            "options": [
                "Semantic error",
                "Logical error",
                "Syntax error",
                "computational error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Semantic error"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python 2, the following code yields\n\nprint 17/10",
            "options": [
                "1.0",
                "1",
                "1.7",
                "1.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Python 3, the following code yields\n\nprint(17/10)",
            "options": [
                "1.0",
                "1",
                "1.7",
                "1.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1.7"
        },
        {
            "question": "In python, -17 % 10 yields",
            "options": [
                "7",
                "3",
                "-7",
                "-3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The arithmetic symbol ** stands for _____________ in Python",
            "options": [
                "exponentiation",
                "module",
                "multiplication",
                "square root"
            ],
            "correctOption": "exponentiation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following Python program?\n\nprint(8.5 % 3.5)",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "5.0",
                "1",
                "1.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1.5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The order of evaluating an arithmetic expression is also called _____________",
            "options": [
                "uniformity",
                "switch",
                "precedence",
                "limits"
            ],
            "correctOption": "precedence"
        },
        {
            "question": "The name given to a memory location is known as _____________",
            "options": [
                "assignment",
                "variable",
                "data",
                "precedence"
            ],
            "correctOption": "variable"
        },
        {
            "question": "x-=80 means?",
            "options": [
                "increment x by 80",
                "decrement x by 80",
                "error",
                "no output"
            ],
            "correctOption": "decrement x by 80"
        },
        {
            "question": "d = 0\nd *= 3 + 4\n\nWhat is the value of 'd' in the program above?",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "7",
                "1",
                "14"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate the below code?\n\nabs(-8/4) ",
            "options": [
                "-2",
                "0",
                "2",
                "1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "All except one can be defined as a collection",
            "options": [
                "array",
                "tuple",
                "list",
                "index"
            ],
            "correctOption": "index"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of 'B' in the following program?\nA = [1,2,3,4,5,6,7]\n B = A[2]**A[6]",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "218",
                "2187",
                "200"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2187"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nA = ['Abuja', 'Naraguta', 'Village', 'Zion']\nprint(len(A[1])*4)",
            "options": [
                "2",
                "8",
                "16",
                "32"
            ],
            "correctOption": "32"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nS = 'welcome to university of Jos'\nprint(len(S))",
            "options": [
                "29",
                "25",
                "30",
                "24"
            ],
            "correctOption": "29"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\ndef m(x,y):\n\treturn x*y\n\nprint(m(3,6))",
            "options": [
                "16",
                "17",
                "18",
                "9",
                "216"
            ],
            "correctOption": "18"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nS = 'Welcome to computer science'\n print(S[3:7])",
            "options": [
                "come",
                "welcome",
                "computer",
                "science"
            ],
            "correctOption": "come"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nprint(float(60)/int(60))",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "0.0",
                "1",
                "1.0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1.0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nx = 3\nx -= 6\nprint(x * 4)",
            "options": [
                "16",
                "-16",
                "-12",
                "12"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-12"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nS='I love Computers'\nprint(len(S.split()))",
            "options": [
                "14",
                "3",
                "12",
                "6"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nS='male'\nprint(S.upper())",
            "options": [
                "MALE",
                "male",
                "Male",
                "MalE",
                "male.upper()",
                "^male^"
            ],
            "correctOption": "MALE"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nif (3 % 12) < 3:\n\tprint 'low'\nelse:\n\tprint 'high'",
            "options": [
                "low",
                "high",
                "lowhigh",
                "highlow"
            ],
            "correctOption": "high"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\nprint (34 < 3**8) | (not(2 < 3))",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "True",
                "30",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following logical operators has the highest precedence?",
            "options": [
                "AND",
                "OR",
                "NOT",
                "None of them"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NOT"
        },
        {
            "question": "Multiplication and addition have equal operator precedence",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "Not Really"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Subtraction and exponentiation have equal operator precedence",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "Not Really"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Multiplication has higher operator precedence than Addition",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "Not Really"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Subtraction has higher operator precedence than Division",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "Not Really"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Relational expression returns its answer as a _____________",
            "options": [
                "boolean",
                "numeral",
                "string",
                "decimal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "boolean"
        },
        {
            "question": "A good program runs fast and consumes a lot of memory",
            "options": [
                "true",
                "false",
                "sometimes",
                "always"
            ],
            "correctOption": "false"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of packaging a program to run on other machines is ______________",
            "options": [
                "configuration",
                "transcription",
                "compilation",
                "debugging",
                "packaging"
            ],
            "correctOption": "compilation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evolution in computers focused on all but one of the following",
            "options": [
                "Speed",
                "Memory",
                "Portability",
                "Branding"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Branding"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following has the smallest physical size?",
            "options": [
                "Vacuum Tubes",
                "Transistors",
                "Silicon computer chips",
                "Integrated Circuits"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Silicon computer chips"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a major limitation of Vacuum Tube computers?",
            "options": [
                "Enormous size",
                "Heat dissipation",
                "Aesthetics",
                "Low performance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Aesthetics"
        },
        {
            "question": "The term 'Computer' is derived from ____________ language",
            "options": [
                "Latin",
                "German",
                "French",
                "Arabic"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Latin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the inventor of the Difference Engine?",
            "options": [
                "Allen Turing",
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Simur Cray",
                "Augusta Adaming"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the father of Computers?",
            "options": [
                "Alan Turing",
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Simur Cray",
                "Augusta Adaming"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the father of Modern Computer Science?",
            "options": [
                "Alan Turing",
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Simur Cray",
                "Augusta Adaming"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Alan Turing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the father of the Personal Computer (PC)?",
            "options": [
                "Edward Robert",
                "Allen Turing",
                "Charles Babbage",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Edward Robert"
        },
        {
            "question": "A CPU contains ______________",
            "options": [
                "a card reader and a printing device",
                "an analytical engine and a control unit",
                "a control unit and an arithmetic logic unit",
                "an arithmetic logic unit and a card reader"
            ],
            "correctOption": "a control unit and an arithmetic logic unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following controls the process of interaction between the user and the operating system?",
            "options": [
                "User interface",
                "Language translator",
                "Platform",
                "Screen saver"
            ],
            "correctOption": "User interface"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first computers were programmed using",
            "options": [
                "assembly language",
                "machine language",
                "source code",
                "object code"
            ],
            "correctOption": "machine language"
        },
        {
            "question": "A/An ____________ is a combination of hardware and software that facilitates the sharing of information between computing devices",
            "options": [
                "Network",
                "peripheral",
                "expansion board",
                "digital device"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Network"
        },
        {
            "question": "Coded entries which are used to gain access to a computer system are called",
            "options": [
                "Entry codes",
                "Passwords",
                "Security commands",
                "Code words"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Passwords"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
            "options": [
                "Minicomputer works faster than Microcomputer",
                "Microcomputer works faster than Minicomputer",
                "Speed of both the computers is the same",
                "The speeds of both these computers cannot be compared with the speed of advanced computers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Minicomputer works faster than Microcomputer"
        },
        {
            "question": "You organize files by storing them in ______________",
            "options": [
                "archives",
                "folders",
                "indexes",
                "lists"
            ],
            "correctOption": "folders"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of resource is most likely to be a shared common resource in a computer network?",
            "options": [
                "Printer",
                "Speaker",
                "Floppy disk drive",
                "Keyboard"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Printer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What device is required for an Internet connection?",
            "options": [
                "Joystick",
                "Modem",
                "CD Drive",
                "NIC Card"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Modem"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a light pen?",
            "options": [
                "A Mechanical Input device",
                "Optical input device",
                "Electronic input device",
                "Optical output device"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Optical input device"
        },
        {
            "question": "UNIVAC stands for",
            "options": [
                "Universal Automatic Computer",
                "Universal Array Computer",
                "Unique Automatic Computer ",
                "Unvalued Automatic Computer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Universal Automatic Computer"
        },
        {
            "question": "CD-ROM stands for",
            "options": [
                "Compactable Read Only Memory",
                "Compact Data Read Only Memory",
                "Compactable Disk Read Only Memory",
                "Compact Disk Read Only Memory"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Compact Disk Read Only Memory"
        },
        {
            "question": "ALU is short for",
            "options": [
                "Array Logic Unit",
                "Application Logic Unit",
                "None of the options",
                "Arithmetic Logic Unit"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Arithmetic Logic Unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "VGA means",
            "options": [
                "Video Graphics Array",
                "Visual Graphics Array",
                "Volatile Graphics Array",
                "Video Graphics Adapter"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Video Graphics Array"
        },
        {
            "question": "The IBM 1401 was/is a _____________",
            "options": [
                "First Generation Computer",
                "Second Generation Computer",
                "Third Generation Computer",
                "Fourth Generation Computer",
                "Fifth Generation Computer",
                "Sixth Generation Computer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Second Generation Computer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a part of the Central Processing Unit?",
            "options": [
                "Printer",
                "Keyboard",
                "Mouse",
                "Arithmetic & Logic unit"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Arithmetic & Logic unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "A computer cannot boot if it does not have the _____________",
            "options": [
                "Compiler",
                "Operating System",
                "Loader",
                "Assembler"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Operating System"
        },
        {
            "question": "The amount of vertical space between lines of text in a document is called _____________",
            "options": [
                "double space",
                "line spacing",
                "single space",
                "vertical spacing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "line spacing"
        },
        {
            "question": "First page of Website is termed its _____________",
            "options": [
                "Homepage",
                "Index",
                "JavaScript",
                "Bookmark",
                "Google result"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Homepage"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are data and program stored when the processor uses them?",
            "options": [
                "Main memory",
                "Secondary memory",
                "Disk memory",
                "Program memory"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Main memory"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ represents raw facts, where as ____________ is data made meaningful",
            "options": [
                "Information, reporting",
                "Data, information",
                "Information, bits",
                "Records, bytes"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Data, information"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which programming languages are classified as low level languages?",
            "options": [
                "BASIC, COBOL, Fortran",
                "Prolog, Lisp",
                "C, C++",
                "Assembly languages"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Assembly languages"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a storage device?",
            "options": [
                "Tape",
                "Hard Disk",
                "Floppy Disk",
                "All of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All of the options"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did John Napier develop logarithms?",
            "options": [
                "1416",
                "1614",
                "1641",
                "1804"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1614"
        },
        {
            "question": "The chief component of first generation computers were",
            "options": [
                "Transistors",
                "Vacuum Tubes and Valves",
                "Integrated Circuits",
                "None of options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Vacuum Tubes and Valves"
        },
        {
            "question": "FORTRAN is derived from ______________",
            "options": [
                "File Translation",
                "Formula Translation",
                "Formula Translator",
                "Format Translation",
                "Floppy Translation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Formula Translation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Personal computers use a number of chips which are mounted on a main circuit board. What is the common name for such boards?",
            "options": [
                "Daughterboard",
                "Motherboard",
                "Brotherboard",
                "Fatherboard",
                "Breadboard"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Motherboard"
        },
        {
            "question": "A computer program that converts an entire program into machine language is called a/an _____________",
            "options": [
                "Interpreter",
                "Simulator",
                "Compiler",
                "Commander"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Compiler"
        },
        {
            "question": "DOS in the context of operating systems stands for _____________",
            "options": [
                "Disk Operating System",
                "Disk operating session",
                "Digital Operating System",
                "Digital Open system",
                "Denial Of Service"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Disk Operating System"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is also known as the brain of a computer?",
            "options": [
                "Control Unit",
                "Central Processing Unit",
                "Arithmetic and Language Unit",
                "Monitor",
                "Synapse",
                "Neural Net"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Central Processing Unit"
        },
        {
            "question": "1 Byte = ?",
            "options": [
                "16 bits",
                "8 bits",
                "4 bits",
                "2 bits",
                "9 bits"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8 bits"
        },
        {
            "question": "BIOS stands for",
            "options": [
                "Basic Input Output system",
                "Binary Input output system",
                "Basic Input Off system",
                "All of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Basic Input Output system"
        },
        {
            "question": "The instructions that tell a computer how to carry out the processing tasks are referred to as computer ____________",
            "options": [
                "programs",
                "processors",
                "input devices",
                "memory modules"
            ],
            "correctOption": "programs"
        },
        {
            "question": "The area of a computer system that temporarily holds data waiting to be processed is ____________",
            "options": [
                "CPU",
                "Memory",
                "Storage",
                "File"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Memory"
        },
        {
            "question": "Data becomes ____________ when it is presented in a format that people can understand and use",
            "options": [
                "processed",
                "graphs",
                "information",
                "presentation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "information"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ is computer software designed to operate the computer hardware and to provide platform for running application software",
            "options": [
                "Application Software",
                "System Software",
                "Software",
                "Operating System"
            ],
            "correctOption": "System Software"
        },
        {
            "question": "The task of performing operations like arithmetic and logical operations is performed specifically by the ____________",
            "options": [
                "ALU",
                "AU",
                "CPU",
                "CU",
                "MMU",
                "UJ"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ALU"
        },
        {
            "question": "The task of performing operations like arithmetic and logical operations is called ____________",
            "options": [
                "Processing",
                "Storing",
                "Editing",
                "Sorting"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Processing"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ALU and Control Unit jointly form the _____________",
            "options": [
                "RAM",
                "ROM",
                "CPU",
                "PC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "CPU"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ALU and Control Unit make up the _____________",
            "options": [
                "RAM",
                "ROM",
                "CPU",
                "PC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "CPU"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following is NOT a programming language",
            "options": [
                "MS-Excel",
                "BASIC",
                "COBOL",
                "C++"
            ],
            "correctOption": "MS-Excel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following is NOT a programming language",
            "options": [
                "Visual Studio",
                "BASIC",
                "Malbolge",
                "C++"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Visual Studio"
        },
        {
            "question": "COBOL is an acronym for____________ ",
            "options": [
                "Common Business Oriented Language",
                "Computer Business Oriented Language",
                "Common Business Operated Language",
                "Common Business Organized Language"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Common Business Oriented Language"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a basic function of a computer?",
            "options": [
                "Storing data",
                "Accepting input",
                "Processing data",
                "Copying text"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Copying text"
        },
        {
            "question": "A person who uses his expertise to gain access to other people's computers to get information illegally or to do damage is a/an _____________",
            "options": [
                "hacker",
                "spammer",
                "instant messenger",
                "programmer",
                "terrorist"
            ],
            "correctOption": "hacker"
        },
        {
            "question": "A lady who uses her expertise to gain access to other people's computers to get information illegally or to do damage is a/an _____________",
            "options": [
                "hacker",
                "spammer",
                "witch",
                "programmer",
                "terrorist",
                "hackstress"
            ],
            "correctOption": "hacker"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cannot be a binary number value?",
            "options": [
                "001",
                "101",
                "202",
                "110"
            ],
            "correctOption": "202"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the program block below?\n\nx=0\nfor i in range(30):\n\tx+=1\nprint x",
            "options": [
                "29",
                "30",
                "31",
                "300"
            ],
            "correctOption": "30"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the program block below?\n\nx=10\nfor i in range(10,2,2):\n\tx-=1\nprint x",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "20",
                "30",
                "40"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "Select the appropriate output of the program below\n\nfor i in range(100):\n\tif i%20 == 0:\n\t\tprint i,",
            "options": [
                "20 100",
                "20 40 60 80",
                "40 60 80",
                "0 20 40 60 80"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0 20 40 60 80"
        },
        {
            "question": "Determine the output of the following program\n\nprint (3 < 5) and not(3 > 5)",
            "options": [
                "15",
                "30",
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "A/An ____________ is an immutable sequence of Python objects",
            "options": [
                "Array",
                "List",
                "Tuple",
                "String"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Tuple"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is not a data type in Python",
            "options": [
                "Link",
                "List",
                "Tuple",
                "Dictionary"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Link"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following function returns the minimum alphabetical character from a string, str?",
            "options": [
                "str.lower()",
                "str.lstrip()",
                "max(str)",
                "min(str)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "min(str)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of L[2] if L = [1,2,3]?",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "None of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following functions compares elements of two dictionaries dict1, dict2?",
            "options": [
                "max(dict)",
                "min(dict)",
                "len(dict)",
                "None of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of the options"
        },
        {
            "question": "Python language supports the following types of operators except",
            "options": [
                "Arithmetic Operators",
                "Comparison (Relational) Operators",
                "Logical Operators",
                "Machine Operators"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Machine Operators"
        },
        {
            "question": "The symbol % stands for",
            "options": [
                "Modulus",
                "Exponent",
                "Division",
                "Addition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Modulus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In python language, the symbol // represents _____________",
            "options": [
                "comment",
                "floor division",
                "modulus",
                "review"
            ],
            "correctOption": "floor division"
        },
        {
            "question": "Arrays in Python and C++ are _________ indexed",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "dual"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Arrays in Python and C++ are zero indexed",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Strings spanning multiple lines can be created in python using ''' .... ''' (Three quotes)",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a valid name for an identifier?",
            "options": [
                "Miles",
                "3Musketeers",
                "The space",
                "Three%ofFifty"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Miles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "Miles",
                "Root_of_2",
                "Root­of­2",
                "Erase"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Root­of­2"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "The space",
                "Nospace",
                "Correct",
                "Verycorrect"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The space"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "3Musketeers",
                "Musketeers3",
                "M3usketeers",
                "_Musketeers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3Musketeers"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is not a type of loop",
            "options": [
                "for loop",
                "data loop",
                "while loop",
                "nested loop"
            ],
            "correctOption": "data loop"
        },
        {
            "question": "In python language, pow(x,y) can be written as____________",
            "options": [
                "x*y",
                "x/y",
                "y**x",
                "x**y"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x**y"
        }
    ]
}